Kang-wook Kim

🗹 full324@snu.ac.kr | 줌 kwkim.me | 🞧 wookladin | 🛅 Kang-wook Kim

SUMMARY

I am an undergraduate student majoring in ECE at Seoul National University. I am working as a research intern at Supertone Inc. Before that, I worked as Senior Al Scientist in MINDsLab. My research interest lies in speech synthesis and generative models.

My goal is to make user-friendly Al services or techniques which can benefit humans. I always focus on improving the usability of my AI model from the user's point of view, and I love these works.

EXPERIENCE

MINDsLab Inc.

Mar. 2020 - Mar. 2022 Senior Al Scientist Pangyo, Kyeonggi

 Worked as the leader of speech synthesis team, making Text-to-Speech (TTS) architectures and training recipes that were widely used such as the donation system of Twitch, weather forecast, and Al Human.

- Developed robust autoregressive TTS system to generate long sentences, which can generate a maximum of 10 minutes of speech.
- Improved sound quality and inference speed of TTS system at once, raised mean opinion score from 3.84 to 4.18, which is comparable to **4.47 of ground-truth** value.
- Developed pronunciation evaluation engine for foreigners with the small, unrefined dataset (4hrs, 12 speakers), which achieved 92% accuracy for unseen speaker's dataset.
- Improved the sound quality of the voice conversion system, which achieved mean opinion scores in naturality and **speaker similarity** comparable to ground-truth.
- Worked as a substitute of mandatory military service, 2020.03 2022.02

Supertone Inc. Apr. 2022 - Now Research Intern Seoul

- Working as a research intern (part-time during the semester, full-time during vacation).
- Doing research to increase the phoneme classification accuracy of singing voices.

EDUCATION

Seoul National University

B.S. in Electronical and Computer Engineering (Overall GPA: 3.99/4.30) (Major: 4.07/4.30)

Mar. 2018 - Now

Seoul, Korea

Gyeonggi Science High School for the gifted

High school for gifted students in mathematics, science, and informatics

Mar. 2015 - Feb. 2018

Gyeonggi, Korea

PUBLICATION

Conference

 Kang-wook Kim, Seung-won Park, Junhyeok Lee, and Myun-chul Joe, "Assem-VC: Realistic Voice Conversion by Assembling Modern Speech Synthesis Techniques," Proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2022

Workshop

- Kang-wook Kim and Junhyeok Lee, "Controllable and Interpretable Singing Voice Decomposition via Assem-VC," NeurIPS Workshop on ML for Creativity and Design 2021 (Oral)
- Ki-Ung Song*, Dongseok Shim*, Kang-wook Kim*, Jae-young Lee, Younggeun Kim, "FS-NCSR: Increasing Diversity of the Super-Resolution Space via Frequency Separation and Noise-Conditioned Normalizing Flow," CVPR NTIRE Workshop 2022

Demo Track

 Hyoung-Kyu Song, Sang Hoon Woo, Junhyeok Lee, Seungmin Yang, Hyunjae Cho, Dongho Choi, Kang-wook Kim, Youseong Lee, "Talking Face Generation with Multilingual TTS," CVPR Demo Track 2022

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTION

Assem-VC - voice conversion system (Stars: 203): Official repository of our paper.

UnivNet - vocoder (Stars: 135): I reproduced the results in the paper while official implementation is unavailable.

HONORS and AWARDS

- Presidential scholarship on informatics 2018 2023, fully funded scholarschip for undergrad course
- · Hanseong Sonjaehan Scholarship 2016 2017, 5M KRW per year
- · Exemplary Youth Awards in Gyeonggi-do 2016, Science and Technology sector
- Korea Olympiad in Informatics (KOI) Gold (4th place) at 2015; Silver, Bronze at 2014, 2011.
- Completion of winter school for International Physics Olympiad (IPhO) candidates 2015, 2016